Finding Aid for Edward W. Blakeman Papers, 1909-1963
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Edward W. Blakeman Papers, 1909-1963
Blakeman, Edward W. (Edward William), 1880-1963.
3 linear ft.
85832 Aa 2
Counselor in religious education at the University of Michigan. Correspondence and biographical material; official reports; radio scripts; articles on the religious education of college students; scrapbook, 1933-1943; preliminary reports of a survey of college religious life published in 1942; materials relating to a survey of University alumni who entered religious vocations; and materials relating to Japanese-Americans in Ann Arbor, Michigan during World War II; also correspondence of several of Blakeman's predecessors as counselor in religious education; materials on the Student Christian Association, the Spring Parley, 1930-1942, the Michigan School of Religion, the Michigan Pastors' Conference, 1940-1947, the Michigan Child Guidance Institute and the Conference on Religion, 1940-1941; and photographs.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was received from Mr. Blakeman (donor no. 1460 ) in multiple accessions, 1937-1960.
The collection is open to research.
Subjects:
Blakeman, Edward W. (Edward William), 1880-1963.; Michigan Pastors' Conference (University of Michigan); Michigan School of Religion.; Missionaries.; Takai, Shigeo William; University of Michigan. Office of Religious Affairs.; University of Michigan--Religion.; University of Michigan--Students--Scholarships, fellowships, etc.; World War, 1939-1945.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Blakeman, Edward W. (Edward William), 1880-1963.
Contributors:
Burton, Marion Le Roy, 1874-1925.; Chinese Students' Christian Association in North America.; Douglas, Lloyd C. (Lloyd Cassel), 1877-1951.; Kent, Charles Foster, 1867-1925.; Sperberg, Lester.; Wilgus, Horace L. (Horace La Fayette), 1859-1935.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Scrapbooks.
- Biographical/Personal
  - Vita; brief autobiographical sketch (Box 1)
  - Reprints of writings (Box 1)
- Correspondence
  - 1909-1963, 20 folders (Box 1)
- Topical files
  - Conference on Religion, 1940-1941 (Box 1)
  - Japanese-Americans in World War II (Box 1)
  - Michigan Pastors' Conference, 1940-1947 (Box 1)
  - Michigan Child Guidance Institute (Box 1)
  - Michigan School of Religion (Box 1)
  - Radio scripts
    - Religion for Youth series (Box 1)
    - Religion for Review series (Box 1)
    - 1939-1945 (Box 1)
    - Undated (Box 1)
  - Religious education, University of Michigan (official reports on), 1937-1953 (scattered years) (Box 1)
  - Student Christian Association (Box 1)
  - Veterans affairs (including University of Michigan Veterans Service Bureau) (Box 1)
- Surveys
  - Surveys: religious vocations and comparison of subject concentration and denominational affiliation (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous papers, speeches, surveys, etc., 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Surveys of the administration of religion in various American universities and colleges (2 expandable folders) (Box 2)
  - Religious Callings; A Study of Michigan Graduates who Entered Religious Callings (Box 2)
- Other Materials
  - Scrapbook on religious affairs at the University, 1939-1946 (Box 3)
  - Scrapbook on religious affairs at the University, 1933-1943 (Box 3)
  - Scrapbook of newspaper column, "Dominie Says" 1941-1947 (Box 3)
  - Notebooks re Spring Parleys and Winter Parleys (Box 3)
  - Photographs (Box 3)